what difference between biological
生物学有 什么区别
neural networks and artificial neural
神经网络与人工神经网络
networks is most mysterious captivating
网络是最神秘的迷人
and profound for you first of all
对你来说最 重要的是
there's so much we don't know about
有这么多我们不 知道的
biological neural networks and that's
生物神经网络就是这样
very mysterious and captivating because
非常神秘和迷人，因为
maybe it holds the key to improving our
也许它是改善我们的关键
differential neural networks one of the
差分神经网络之一
things I studied recently something that
但是最近我研究的东西 ，
we don't know how biological neural
我们不知道生物神经学 如何
networks do but would be really useful
网络做但会非常有用
for artificial ones is the ability to do
对于人造的是 能力
credit assignment through very long time
信用分配很长一段时间
spans there are things that we can in
跨越我们可以做的事情
principle do with artificial neural nets
人工神经 网络的原理
but it's not very convenient and it's
但它并不是很方便
not biologically plausible and this
不是生物学合理性 ，这
mismatch I think this kind of mismatch
不匹配我认为这种不匹配
may be an interesting thing to study to
可能是一件 有趣的事情来研究
a understand better how brains might do
更好地了解大脑可能会做什么
these things because we don't have good
这些东西因为我们没有 好处
corresponding theories with artificial
相应的理论与人工
neural Nets and B maybe provide new
神经网络和B可能提供新的
ideas that we could explore about things
我们可以 探索有关事物的 想法
that brain do differently and that we
大脑做得与众不同
could incorporate in artificial neural
可以纳入人工神经网络
Nets so let's break created assignment
篮网让我们打破创造的任务
up a little bit yeah what it's a
一点点是的，这是什么
beautifully technical term but it could
精美的技术术语， 但它可以
incorporate so many things so is it more
包含很多东西， 所以更多
on the RNN memory side that thinking
在RNN记忆方面那个想法
like that or is it something about
喜欢那样或是它的东西
knowledge building up common sense
知识建立 常识
knowledge over time or is it more in the
知识随着 时间的推移 还是 更多的 知识
reinforcement learning sense that you're
你是强化学习的感觉
picking up rewards over time for a
拿起 奖励随着 时间的
particular to achieve certain kind of
特别是要实现某种特定 的
goals so I was thinking more about the
目标 所以我在考虑更多
first two meanings whereby we store all
我们存储 所有的前两个含义
kinds of memories episodic memories in
种记忆 情节记忆 中
our brain which we can access later in
我们以后可以访问的大脑
order to help us both infer causes of
以帮助我们推断原因
things that we are observing now
我们现在正在观察的事情
and assign credit to decisions or
并为决定分配信用
interpretations we came up with a while
解释我们想出了一段时间
ago when you know those memories were
以前当你知道那些记忆的时候
stored and then we can change the way we
存储然后我们可以改变 我们 的方式
would have reacted or interpreted things
会 反应或解释的东西
in the past and now that's credit
在过去和现在，这是值得信赖的
assignment used for learning so in which
用于学习的作业，所以
way do you think artificial neural
你认为人工神经的方式
networks the current LS TM the current
网络当前LS TM的电流
architectures are not able to capture
架构无法捕获
the presumably you're thinking of very
大概是你想的
long term yes so current recurrent Nets
长期 是的，所以目前的经常性篮网
are doing a fairly good jobs for
正在做一个 相当不错的工作
sequences with dozens or say hundreds of
有数十个或数百个的序列
time stamps and then it gets harder and
时间戳，然后它变得更难
harder and depending on what you have to
更难，取决于你 有 什么
remember and so on as you consider
记得等 你考虑的事情
longer durations whereas humans seem to
更长的持续时间，而人类似乎
be able to do credit assignment through
能够通过分配信用
essentially arbitrary times like I could
基本上是我随意的任意时间
remember something I did last year and
记住一些东西，去年我没有 和
then now because I see some new evidence
那么现在因为我看到了一些新的 证据
I'm gonna change my mind about the way I
我 会改变自己的想法
was thinking last year and hopefully not
去年正在思考，希望不是
do the same mistake again I think a big
再犯同样的错误我觉得很大
part of that is probably forgetting
其中一部分可能会遗忘
you're only remembering the really
你 只记得 真的
important things it's very efficient
重要的是它非常有效
forgetting yes so there's a selection of
遗忘是这么有的选择
what we remember and I think there are
我们还记得，我想有
really cool connection to higher-level
真正很酷的连接到更高级别
cognition here regarding consciousness
这里对意识的认识
deciding and and emotions like sort of
决定和情绪一样
deciding what comes to consciousness and
决定什么来到意识和
what gets stored in memory which which
什么存储在内存中哪个
are not trivial either so you've been at
也不 是那么 简单 ，所以你 去过
the forefront there all along showing
一直在那里展示的最前沿
some of the amazing things that neural
一些神奇的神奇 事物
networks deep neural networks can do in
网络深度神经网络 可以做到
the field of artificial intelligence is
人工智能领域是
just broadly in all kinds of
各种各样的广泛
applications but we can talk about that
申请，但我们可以谈论 这个
forever but what in your view because
永远， 但你认为是什么
we're thinking towards the future is the
我们正在思考 未来的发展方向
weakest aspect of the way deep neural
深层神经的方式最薄弱
networks represent the world what is
网络代表着世界 是什么
that what is in your view is missing so
您认为的内容是如此缺失
currently current state-of-the-art
目前最先进的
neural nets trained on large quantities
神经 网络 大量训练
of images or texts have some level of
图像或文本有一定的水平
understanding of you know what explains
了解你 知道什么解释
those datasets but it's very basic it's
那些数据集，但它是非常 基础的
it's very low-level and it's not nearly
这是非常低级别 ， 并不是很近
as robust and abstract in general as our
像我们一样强大而抽象
understanding okay so that doesn't tell
理解 好， 所以不说
us how to fix things but I think it
我们如何解决的事情， 但我认为 这
encourages us to think about how we can
鼓励我们 思考 如何做到
maybe train our neural nets differently
也许训练我们的神经网络不同
so that they would focus for example on
因此， 他们将集中 例如 在
causal explanations something that we
因果解释是我们的事
don't do currently with neural net
目前不做神经网络
training also one thing I'll talk about
训练也是我要谈的一件事
in my talk this afternoon is instead of
在我的谈话今天 下午是不是
learning separately from images and
与图像分开学习
videos on one hand and from text on the
一方面是视频，另一方面是文字
other hand we need to do a better job of
另一方面我们需要做得更好
jointly learning about language and
共同学习语言和
about the world to which it refers so
关于它所指的世界
that you know both sides can help each
你知道双方都可以提供帮助
other we need to have good world models
其他我们需要有良好的世界模型
in our neural nets for them to really
在 我们的 神经 网中 为他们提供真正的
understand sentences which talk about
理解谈论的句子
what's going on in the world and I think
我认为 世界上发生了什么
we need language input to help provide
我们需要语言输入 来帮助提供
clues about what high-level concepts
关于什么是高级概念的线索
like semantic concepts should be
像语义概念应该 是
represented at the top levels of these
代表了这些的顶级水平
neural nets in fact there is evidence
神经网实际上有证据
that the purely unsupervised learning of
纯粹无监督的学习
representations doesn't give rise to
表示不产生
high level representations that are as
高级别的表示 形式
powerful as the ones we are getting from
像我们得到的那样强大
supervised learning
监督学习
and so the the clues we're getting just
所以我们得到的线索 正好
with the labels not even sentences is
与唱片公司甚至没有句子 是
already very powerful do you think
你觉得你已经非常强大了
that's an architecture challenge or is
这是一个架构挑战或者是
it a data set challenge neither I'm
它不是一个数据集挑战我
tempted to just end it there in your
试着 在你的身边结束它
library of course data sets and
当然数据 集和 库
architectures are something you want to
架构是你想要的
always play with but but I think the
总是打不过，但我认为 ，
crucial thing is more the training
关键的是更多的培训
objectives the training frameworks for
目标培训框架
example going from passive observation
从被动观察开始的例子
of data to more active agents which
数据到更活跃的代理商
learn by intervening in the world the
在世界介入学习
relationships between causes and effects
原因和结果之间的关系
the sort of objective functions which
那种 客观功能
could be important to allow the the
可能很重要，允许
highest level explanations to to to rise
最高级别的解释， 以上涨
from from the learning which I don't
来自我不学习的东西
think we have now the kinds of objective
我们认为我们现在 有各种各样的目标
functions which could be used to reward
可以用来奖励的功能
exploration the right kind of
探索正确的那种
exploration so these kinds of questions
探索所以这些问题
are neither in the dataset nor in the
既不在数据集中也不在数据集中
architecture but more in how we learn
建筑， 但更多 的是我们如何学习
under what objectives and so on yeah
在什么目标下等等
that's a afraid you mentioned in several
你害怕在几个人中提到这一点
contexts the idea is sort of the way
上下文这个想法就是 这样
children learn they interact with
孩子们学习他们互动
objects of the world and it seems
似乎 是世界的对象
fascinating because it's some sense
令人着迷，因为它有一定道理
except with some cases in reinforcement
除了一些加固案例
learning that idea is not part of the
学习这个想法不 属于
learning process in artificial neural
人工神经学习过程
network so it's almost like do you
网络所以它几乎像你一样
envision something like an objective
设想像客观的东西
function saying you know what if you
功能说你知道如果你
poke this object in this kind of way
以这种方式 戳这个 对象
would be really helpful for me to
对我来说 真的 很有帮助
further
进一步
yes further learn right right sort of
是的进一步学习正确 的
almost guiding some aspect of learning
几乎指导 学习的 某些方面
right right so I was talking to Rebecca
右边所以我 和丽贝卡说话
Saxe just an hour ago and she was
Saxe就在一小时前， 她就是
talking about lots and lots of evidence
谈论很多 很多证据
for
对于
infants seem to clearly take what
婴儿似乎清楚地 采取了什么
interest them in a directed way and so
他们以 有针对性的方式 对 他们 感兴趣
they're not passive learners they they
他们不是被动的学习者，他们自己
focus their attention on aspects of the
把注意力集中在方方面面
world which are most interesting
最有趣的世界
surprising in in a non-trivial way that
以一种非平凡的方式令人惊讶
makes them change their theories of the
让他们改变他们的理论
world so that's a fascinating view of
世界，这是一个迷人的观点
the future progress but Anna the more
未来的进步，但 安娜更多
maybe boring a question do you think
也许你觉得这个问题很无聊
going deeper and large so do you think
越深越大， 你认为
just increasing the size of the things
刚刚增加的 大小 事
that have been increasing a lot in the
一直在增加很多
past few years will will also make
过去几年 也会做出来的
significant progress so some of the
一些重要进展
representational issues that you
你的代表性问题
mentioned that is they're kind of
提到那是 他们的一种
shallow in some sense Oh higher in a
浅在某种意义上处于较高 哦
sense of abstraction up straight in a
直观的抽象感
sense of abstraction they're not getting
他们没有得到的抽象感
some I don't think that having more more
有些我不 认为有更多
depth in the network in the sense of
在网络中的深度意义上讲
instead of a hundred layers we have ten
而不是一百层我们有十层
thousand is going to solve our problem
千人将解决 我们的 问题
you don't think so is that obvious to
你不这么认为那是显而易见的
you yes what is clear to me is that
你是什么我很清楚 的 是 ，
engineers and companies and labs grad
工程师，公司和实验室 毕业生
students will continue to tune
学生将继续调整
architectures and explore all kinds of
建筑和探索各种各样的
tweaks to make the current state of the
调整，使目前的状态
Arts that he ever slightly better but I
艺术，他有点好，但我
don't think that's gonna be nearly
不要 以为那会 差不多
enough I think we need some fairly
我认为我们需要一些公平的
drastic changes in the way that we're
我们的方式发生了巨大的变化
considering learning to achieve the goal
考虑学习实现 目标
that these learners actually understand
这些学习者 真正理解
in a deep way the environment in which
在深层次的环境中
they are you know observing and acting
他们是你知道观察和表演的
but I guess I was trying to ask a
但我想我试图 问一个
question is more interesting than just
问题比仅仅更有趣
more layers is basically once you figure
更多层次基本上就是你想象的
out a way to learn through interacting
通过互动学习一种方式
how many parameters does it take to
多少个参数， 没有考虑到
store that information so
存储这些信息， 以便
I think our brain is quite bigger than
我认为我们的大脑 比大
most neural networks right right oh I
大多数神经网络对了哦我
see what you mean oh I I'm with you
明白你的意思哦，我和 你在一起
there so I agree that in order to build
所以我同意为了建立
neural nets with the kind of broad
具有 广泛的 神经 网络
knowledge of the world that typical
世界是典型 的知识
adult humans have probably the kind of
成人有可能的 那种
computing power we have now is going to
计算现在我们已经打算电源
be insufficient so well the good news is
这个好 消息 是 不够的
there are hardware companies building
有硬件公司建设
neural net chips and so it's gonna get
神经网络芯片，所以它会得到
better however the good news in a way
但是在某种程度上好消息
which is also a bad news is that even
这甚至 是 一个坏消息
our state-of-the-art deep learning
我们 最先进的深度学习
methods fail to learn models that
方法无法学习那些模型
understand even very simple environments
了解甚至非常简单的环境
like some Grid worlds that we have built
就像 我们建立的 一些网格 世界 一样
even these fairly simple environments I
即便是这些相当简单的环境我
mean of course if you train them with
当然，如果你训练他们的意思
enough examples eventually they get it
足够的例子最终他们得到它
but it's just like instead of what
但它 只是喜欢而不是什么
instead of what humans might need just
而不是人类可能只需要
dozens of examples these things will
这些事情会有 几十 例
need millions right for very very very
非常非常需要数百万人
simple tasks and so I think there's an
简单的任务，所以我认为有一个
opportunity for academics who don't have
没有学者的机会
the kind of computing power that say
那种计算能力 是说
Google has to do really important and
谷歌必须做的 非常重要
exciting research to advance the
激动人心的 研究 推进
state-of-the-art in training frameworks
培训框架中的最新技术
learning models agent learning in even
学习模特代理学习甚至
simple environments that are synthetic
简单的合成环境
that seem trivial but yet current
这似乎是微不足道但却是最新的
machine learning fails on we've talked
我们谈过机器学习失败了
about priors and common-sense knowledge
关于先辈和常识知识
it seems like we humans take a lot of
似乎我们 人类需要花费很多
knowledge for granted so what what's
知识是理所当然的，那是什么
your view of these priors of forming
您 对这些形成先验的 看法
this broad view of the world this
这个世界的广阔视野
accumulation of information and how we
积累信息 以及 我们 如何
can teach a neural networks or learning
可以教授神经网络或学习
systems to pick that knowledge up so
系统来挑选这些知识
knowledge you know for a while the
你知道一段时间的知识
artificial intelligence what's maybe in
人工智能 什么是可能的
the 80 there's a time or knowledge
80有时间或知识
representation knowledge
代表性知识
acquisition expert systems I mean though
我的意思是收购专家系统
the symbolic AI was was a view was an
象征性的AI是一个观点是一个
interesting problem set to solve and it
有趣的问题设置解决它
was kind of put on hold a little bit it
有点搁置了一点
seems like because it doesn't work it
似乎是因为它不起作用
doesn't work that's right but that's
不行，那是正确的，但那 是
right but the goals of that remain
是的， 但目标 仍然存在
important yes remain important kind of
重要的是仍然是重要的 一种
how do you think those goals can be
你觉得这些目标怎么样？
addressed right so first of all I
解决右所以 首先我的
believe that one reason why the
相信这就是其中一个 原因
classical expert systems approach failed
经典专家系统方法失败
is because a lot of the knowledge we
是因为很多 知识，我们 的
have so you talked about common sense
所以你 谈到了常识
intuition there's a lot of knowledge
直觉有很多 知识
like this which is not consciously
这是不自觉的
accessible the lots of decisions we're
我们可以做出很多决定
taking that we can't really explain even
接受我们甚至无法解释
if sometimes we make up a story and that
如果有时我们编造一个故事 而且那个
knowledge is also necessary for machines
机器也需要知识
to take good decisions and that
做出正确的决定
knowledge is hard to codify in expert
知识很难在专家中编纂
systems rule-based systems and you know
系统基于规则的系统，你知道
Costco EAJA formalism and there are
Costco EAJA形式主义也有
other issues of course with the old AI
其他问题当然与旧 AI有关
like not really good ways of handling
喜欢不是很好的处理方式
uncertainty I would say something more
不确定性我会说更多
subtle which we understand better now
我们现在明白了的微妙之处
but I think still isn't enough in the
但我 认为仍然是不够 的
minds of people there is something
人们的思想有一些东西
really powerful that comes from
非常强大的来自
distributed representations the thing
分布式表示事物
that really makes neural Nets work so
这真的让神经网络如此运作
well and it's hard to replicate that
好，这是很难 复制这种
kind of power in a symbolic world the
在象征世界中的那种力量
knowledge in in expert systems and so on
在专家系统等方面的知识
is nicely decomposed into like a bunch
很好地 分解成一堆
of rules whereas if you think about a
规则，而如果你考虑一个
neural net it's the opposite you have
神经网络是你 有 相反的
this big blob of parameters which work
这大块参数有效
intensely together to represent
强烈地共同代表
everything the network knows and it's
网络知道的一切都是如此
not sufficiently factorized and so I
没有充分分解 ，所以 我
think this is one of the weaknesses of
认为这是其中一个 缺点
current neural nets that we have to take
我们必须采取的当前神经网络
lessons from classically I
经典的教训我
in order to bring in another kind of
为了带来另一种
compositionality which is common in
在...中常见的组合性
language for example and in these rules
例如，语言和这些规则
but that isn't so native to New Ulm Ed's
但这并不是New Ulm Ed的 原生
and on that line of thinking
并在那条思路上
disentangled representations yes so so
解开的陈述 是如此
let me connect with disentangled
让我联系解开
representations if you might if don't
表达，如果你可能不这样做
mind yes exactly so for many years I've
心灵 是那么究竟多年 我已经
thought and I still believe that it's
想到了，我仍然 相信它
really important that we come up with
我们提出的 非常重要
learning algorithms either unsupervised
学习算法要么 无人监督
or supervised but or enforcement
或监督但执法
whatever that build representations in
无论是构建申述
which the important factors hopefully
哪些是重要的因素
causal factors are nicely separated and
因果因素很好地分开了
easy to pick up from the representation
很容易从代表中提取
so that's the idea of disentangle
这就是 解开 思想的想法
representations it says transform the
它表示转换的表示
data into a space where everything
数据进入一切 空间
becomes easy we can maybe just learn
变得容易我们也许 可以学习
with linear models about the things we
关于我们的事物的线性模型
care about and and I still think this is
关心和我仍然认为这是
important but I think this is missing
重要，但我认为这是缺失的
out on a very important ingredient which
出一个非常重要的成分
classically AI systems can remind us of
经典的 AI系统可以提醒 我们
so let's say we have these design
所以我们说我们有这些设计
technologies invation
技术 邀请
you still need to learn about the the
你还需要了解它
relationships between the variables
变量之间的关系
those high-level semantic variables
那些高级语义变量
they're not going to be independent I
他们不会独立 我
mean this is like too much of an
意思是这太像 了
assumption they're gonna have some
假设他们会有一些
interesting relationships that allow to
有趣的关系，允许
predict things in the future to explain
预测未来的事情要解释
what happened in the past the kind of
过去 那种什么事
knowledge about those relationships in a
关于这些关系的知识
classically AI system is encoded in the
经典的AI系统编码在
rules like a rule is just like a little
像规则这样的规则就像一点点
piece of knowledge that says oh I have
一块 知识 ，说啊，我有
these two three four variables that are
这两个三个四个变量是
linked in this interesting way then I
我以这种有趣的方式联系起来
can say something about one or two of
可以说 一两个
them given a couple of others right in
他们赋予的权利在其他几个
addition to disentangling the the
除了解开之外
elements of the representation which are
表示的元素是
like the variables in rule-based system
像基于规则的系统中的变量
you also need to disentangle the the
你还需要解开 它
mechanisms that relate those variables
与这些变量相关的机制
to each other so like the rules so the
彼此如此喜欢规则 所以
rules are neatly separated like each
规则整齐地 分开，就像每个
rule is you know living on its own and
规则是你知道独自生活和
when I change a rule because I'm
当我改变规则因为 我是
learning
学习
it doesn't need to break other rules
它不需要 打破其他规则
whereas current your Mets for example
而目前 你的大都会队 就是这样
are very sensitive to what's called
对所谓的内容非常敏感
catastrophic forgetting where after I've
灾难性遗忘我忘记了
learned some things and then I learn new
学到了一些东西，然后我学到了新东西
things they can destroy the old things
他们可以 破坏旧事物的东西
that I had learned right if the
我 已经学会了如果
knowledge was better factorized and and
知识更好地分解和
separated disentangled then you would
分开解开然后你会
avoid a lot of that now you can't do
现在 你不能做很多事
this in the sensory domain but a decent
这在感官领域，但一个体面
okay like an pixel space but but my idea
好像像素空间，但我的想法
is that when you project the data in the
是在你投影 数据时
right semantic space it becomes possible
正确的语义空间变得可能
to now represent this extra knowledge
现在 代表这种额外的知识
beyond the transformation from input to
超越从输入转变为
representations which is how
表示是如何
representations act on each other and
陈述相互作用和
predict the future and so on in a way
以某种方式预测未来等等
that can be neatly disentangled so now
现在可以解开整齐如此
it's the rules or disentangle from each
这是各自 的规则或解开
other and not just the variables that
其他而不仅仅是变量
are disentangled from each other and you
彼此和 你一起解开了
draw a distinction between semantic
区分语义
space and pixel like yes there need to
像是的空间和像素需要
be an architectural difference or well
是一种建筑差异 还是很好
yeah so there's the sensory space like
是的所以感觉空间就像
pixels which where everything is
一切都在哪里的像素
untangled the the information like the
解开 像这样的信息
variables are completely interdependent
变量是完全相互依赖的
in very complicated ways and also
以非常复杂的 方式也是
computation like the it's not just
计算就像它不仅仅是
variables it's also how they are related
变量也是它们的相关方式
to each other is is all intertwined but
相互 之间是相互交织的
but I I'm hypothesizing that in the
但我我假设到， 在
right high-level representation space
正确的高级代表空间
both the variables and how they relate
变量及其相关方式
to each other can be disentangled and
彼此可以被解开
that will provide a lot of
这将提供大量的
generalization power generalization
泛化权力泛化
power yes distribution of the test set
power 是 测试集的 分布
he assumed to be the same as a
他认为是相同的
distribution of the training set right
分配训练集权利
this is where current machine learning
这是当前机器学习的地方
is too weak it doesn't tell us anything
太弱了它没告诉我们什么
is not able to tell us anything about
不能告诉我们 任何事情
how are you let's say our gonna
你怎么说我们 会 说的
generalize to a new distribution and and
概括为一个新的分布 和
you know people may think well but
你知道人们可能会好好思考但是
there's nothing we can say if we don't
如果我们 不这样做 ，我们就 无能为力了
know what the new distribution will be
知道新的发行版会是什么
the truth is humans are able to
事实是人类能够做到的
generalize to new distributions how are
推广到新的发行版是 怎么回事
we able to do that so yeah because
我们 能够做到这一点，因为
something these new distributions even
甚至是这些新发行版的东西
though they could look very different
虽然他们看起来很不一样
from the training solutions they have
从他们的培训解决方案
things in common so let me give you a
共同的 东西 ，所以 让我给你一个
concrete example you read a science
你阅读科学的具体例子
fiction novel the science fiction novel
小说小说 科幻小说
maybe you know brings you in some other
也许你知道带给你其他一些
planet where things look very different
事情看起来非常不同的星球
on the surface but it's still the same
在表面上， 但它 仍然是相同的
laws of physics all right and so you can
物理定律 可以，所以你可以
read the book and you understand what's
读这本书， 你明白了什么
going on
继续
so the distribution is very different
所以分布非常不同
but because you can transport a lot of
但是因为你可以运输很多
the knowledge you had from Earth about
你从 地球 那里得到的知识
the underlying cause and effect
根本原因 和结果
relationships and physical mechanisms
关系和物理机制
and all that and maybe even social
所有这些，甚至可能是社交的
interactions you can now make sense of
你 现在可以理解的互动
what is going on on this planet where
在 这个 星球上发生了什么
like visually for example things are
像视觉例如事情是
totally different
完全不同
taking that analogy further and
进一步采取这种类比
distorting it let's enter a sign science
扭曲它让我们进入一个标志科学
fiction world to say Space Odyssey 2001
小说世界说太空漫游2001
with hell yeah or or maybe which is
与地狱是啊或或许是哪个
probably one of my favourite AI movies
可能是我最喜欢的AI电影之一
and then then - and then there's another
然后- 然后是另一个
one that a lot of people love that it
一个 很多 人都喜欢它 的 人
may be a little bit outside of the AI
可能是AI 的 外面一点点
community is ex machina right I don't
社区是前机器人 我没有
know if you've seen it yes yes but what
知道你是否看到 它 是，但是什么
are your views on that movie alright
你对这部电影的看法还好吗？
does it does are you able to wear things
它能做到你能穿的 东西吗？
I like and things I hate so maybe you
我喜欢和我讨厌的事情，也许你
could talk about that in the context of
在可能的情况下谈论
a question I want to ask which is uh
我想问的问题是呃
there's quite a large community of
有 相当大社区
people from different backgrounds often
经常来自不同背景的人
outside of AI who are concerned about
在人工智能之外关注
existential threat of artificial
人为的存在威胁
intelligence right you've seen now this
你现在看到的情报吧
community develop over time you've seen
社区随着时间的推移而发展
you have a perspective so what do you
你有一个观点，所以你是什么
think is the best way to talk about a a
认为是谈论aa的最佳方式
safety to think about it to have this
考虑到这一点的安全性
course about it within AI community and
关于它在AI社区内的课程和
outside and grounded in the fact that ex
在外面， 并以事实为依据
machina is one of the main sources of
machina 是其中一个主要 来源
information for the general public about
关于公众的 信息
AI so I think I think you're putting it
人工智能所以我想我认为 你是 这样的
right there's a big difference between
右侧有一个很大的 区别
the sort of discussion we oughta have
排序的讨论中，我们现在应该 有
within the AG community and the sort of
在AG社区内和那种
discussion that really matter in the
讨论中，真正 在这个 问题 上
general public
普通大众
so I think the the picture of terminator
所以我认为终结者的图片
and you know AI lose and killing people
而且你知道人工智能会失去并杀死 人
and super intelligence that's gonna
还有超级情报
destroy us whatever we try isn't really
摧毁我们无论 我们尝试的是 什么 都不是
so useful for the public discussion
这对 公众讨论 非常有用
because for the public discussion that
因为对于公众讨论而言
things I believe really matter are the
我认为真正重要的是
short-term and mini term very likely
很可能是 短期 和短期的
negative impacts of AI on society
人工智能对社会的负面影响
whether it's from security like you know
是否来自安全，就像你知道的那样
Big Brother scenarios with face
面对大哥的情景
recognition or killer robots or the
识别或杀手机器人 或
impact on the job market or
对就业市场的影响或
concentration of power and
权力集中和
discrimination all kinds of social
歧视各种社会
issues which could actually some of them
问题 可能实际上 他们中的 一些
could really threaten democracy for
可能真的威胁到民主
example just to clarify when you said
例子只是澄清你说什么时候
killer robots you mean autonomous
杀手机器人你的意思是自主
weapons yes weapon systems yes I do not
武器是武器系统 是的我没有
terminator that's right
终结者 是对的
so I think these these short and
所以我 认为这些简短而且
medium-term concerns should be important
中期问题应该是重要的
parts of the public debate now
现在是公众辩论的一部分
existential risk for me is a very
对我来说存在风险是非常的
unlikely consideration but still worth
不太可能考虑，但仍值得
academic investigation in the same way
同样的学术调查
that you could say should we study what
你可以说我们应该研究什么
could happen if meteorite you know came
如果你认识的陨石来了，就会发生
to earth and destroyed it so I think
我认为 ，地球和摧毁它
it's very unlikely that this is gonna
这是非常不可能的 ，这 是要去
happen and or happen it in a reasonable
发生 或发生在一个合理的
future it's it's very the the sort of
未来它就是那种
scenario of an AI getting loose goes
AI变得松散的情景
against my understanding of at least
反对我的理解至少
current machine learning and current
目前的机器学习和当前
neural nets and so on it's not plausible
神经网络等等不可信
to me but of course I don't have a
我但我当然 没有
crystal ball and who knows what a I will
水晶球 谁知道我会怎样
be in fifty years from now so I think it
从现在开始的五十年，所以我想
is worth at scientists study those
值得科学家研究那些
problems it's just not a pressing
问题不仅仅是紧迫的问题
question as far as I'm concerned so
就我所关心的问题而言
before continuing down the line a few
继续倒行 数 之前
questions there but what what do you
问题存在，但什么你是什么
like and not like about ex machina as a
似与不喜欢 前Machina作为
movie because I I actually watch it for
电影，因为我真的 看着 它
the second time and enjoyed it I hated
第二次，享受它，我讨厌
it the first time and I enjoyed it quite
它的第一次，我 很喜欢它 相当
a bit more the second time when I sort
我排序的第二次多一点
of learned to accept
学会接受
certain pieces of it CC is the concept
CC的 某些部分 是 概念
movie hi what was your experience
电影你喜欢什么？
wouldn't Laura your thoughts so the
不会劳拉你的想法所以
negative is the picture it paints of
负面是它所描绘的画面
science is totally wrong science in
科学是完全错误的科学
general and AI in particular science is
一般而且AI尤其是科学
not happening in some hidden place by
没有发生在一些隐藏的地方
some you know really smart guy one
有些人你 知道真聪明的人
person one person
一个人一个人
this is totally unrealistic this is not
这不完全是不现实的
how it happens
怎么回事
even a team of people in some isolated
甚至是一些孤立的人群
place will not make it
地方不会成功
science moved by small steps thanks to
科学小步走动，感谢
the collaboration and community of a
一个合作和社区
large number of people interacting and
大量的人互动 和
[Music]
[音乐]
all the scientists who are expert in
所有专家的科学家
their field Canon Oh what is going on
他们的领域佳能哦发生了什么 事
even in the industrial labs its
甚至在工业实验室里也是如此
information flows and leaks and so on
信息流和泄漏等
and and and the spirit of it is very
而且它的精神非常
different from the way science is
与科学的方式不同
painted in this movie yeah let me let me
画在这部电影 是的，让我让我
ask on that on that point it's been the
在 这一点 上询问 它是什么
case to this point yeah that kind of
到这一点的情况是的那种
even if the research happens inside
即使研究发生在里面
Google or Facebook inside companies it
谷歌或Facebook内部的公司吧
still kind of comes out like yes come on
仍然有点出来就像是来吧
absolutely think that will always be the
绝对认为这 将永远是
case so there I is is it possible to
案件，所以我有可能
bottle ideas to the point where there's
瓶子的想法到了那里
a set of breakthrough the go completely
一组突破性 的完全去
undiscovered by the general research
一般研究未发现
community do you think that's even
社区你认为这是否均匀
possible it's possible but it's unlikely
可能有可能， 但不太可能
unlikely it's not how it is done now
不可能这不是它是如何做到 现在
it's not how I can foresee it in in the
这不是我怎么能预见到的
foreseeable future but of course I don't
可预见的未来， 但 我当然 不会
have a crystal ball and so who knows
有一个水晶球 ，所以谁知道
this is science fiction after all but
毕竟这是科幻小说
but usually the ominous that the lights
但通常是灯光的不祥之作
went off during during that discussion
在讨论期间发生了变化
so the problem again there's a you know
所以问题又来了，你知道吗
one thing is the movie and you could
有一件事是电影，你 可以
imagine all kinds of science fiction the
想象各种 科幻小说
problem wouldn't for me may be similar
问题不适合我可能 是 类似的
to the question about existential risk
关于存在风险的问题
is that this kind of movie pain
是这种 电影的痛苦
such a wrong picture of what is actual
什么是实际的错误图片
you know the actual science and how it's
你知道实际的科学以及它是如何的
going on that that it can have
继续它可以有
unfortunate effects on people's
对人们的不幸影响
understanding of current science and and
了解当前的科学和
so that's kind of sad is it an important
所以有点难过是一件很重要的事情
principle in research which is diversity
研究中的原则是多样性
so in other words research is
所以换句话说 研究
exploration resources explosion in the
勘探资源爆炸
space of ideas and different people will
思想空间和 不同的人会
focus on different directions and this
专注于不同的 方向和这个
is not just good it's essential so I'm
这不仅仅是好事， 所以我很重要
totally fine with people exploring
与 人探讨完全正常
directions that are contrary to mine or
与 我的 相反的 方向
look orthogonal to mine it's I I am more
看起来与我的正交 我 是我更多
than fine I think it's important I and
我认为 这很重要我和
my friends don't claim we have universal
我的朋友们并没有声称我们拥有普遍性
truth about what well especially about
特别关于什么的真相
what will happen in the future now that
现在 ， 在未来会发生什么
being said we have our intuitions and
据说我们 有自己的直觉和
then we act accordingly according to
然后我们采取相应的行动 ， 根据
where we think we can be most useful and
我们认为我们最有用的地方
where society has the most gain or to
其中，社会拥有最 增益或
lose we should have those debates and
失去我们应该有这些辩论和
and and and not end up in a society
和而不是最终进入一个社会
where there's only one voice and one way
那里只有一个 声音和一个方向
of thinking in research money is spread
在研究金钱 的思想 传播
out so disagreement is a sign of good
如此分歧是好的迹象
research good science so yes the idea of
研究好科学所以是的想法
bias in in the human sense of bias yeah
在人类的偏见中偏见是的
how do you think about instilling in
你怎么看待灌输
machine learning something that's
机器学习东西是
aligned with human values in terms of
在 以下方面与人的价值取向
bias we and intuitively human beings
偏见我们和 直觉上的人类
have a concept of what bias means of
有一个偏见意味着什么的概念
what fundamental respect for other human
什么是对其他人的基本尊重
beings means but how do we instill that
众生意味着但我们如何灌输
into machine learning systems do you
进入 机器学习系统吗？
think so I think there are short-term
这么想我认为有 短期的
things that are already happening and
已经发生的事情和
then there are long-term things that we
那么我们就有长期的事情
need to do and the short term there are
需要做 和短期有
techniques that have been proposed and I
已 提出的技术和我
think will continue to be improved and
认为会继续改进和
maybe alternatives will come up to take
也许会有替代方案
datasets in which we know there is bias
我们知道存在偏见的 数据集
we can measure it pretty much any data
我们几乎可以测量任何数据
set where humans are you know being
设置你知道人类的地方
observed taking decisions will have some
观察到的决定将有一些
sort of bias discrimination against
一种偏见歧视
particular groups and so on and we can
特殊群体 等我们可以
use machine learning techniques to try
用机器学习 技巧来试试
to build predictors classifiers that are
构建预测变量分类器
going to be less biased we can do it for
将 是更加客观，我们可以做到这一点
example using adversarial methods to
例如使用对抗性的方法来
make our systems less sensitive to these
使我们的系统对 这些 不太敏感
variables we should not be sensitive to
变量我们不应该敏感
so these are clear well-defined ways of
所以这些都是明确定义明确的方式
trying to address the problem maybe they
试图解决问题可能是他们
have weaknesses and you know more
有弱点，你知道更多
research is needed and so on but I think
我认为需要研究等等
in fact they are sufficiently mature
事实上他们已经足够成熟了
that governments should start regulating
政府应该开始 监管
companies where it matters say like
有意义的公司就像
insurance companies so that they use
保险公司让他们使用
those techniques because those
那些技术因为那些
techniques will produce the bias but at
技术会产生偏见， 但是
a costs for example maybe their
例如他们的成本
predictions will be less accurate and so
预测将不那么准确等等
companies will not do it until you force
在你逼迫之前，公司不 会这样做
them all right so this is short term
他们没事，所以这是短期的
long term I'm really interested in
长期 我真的很感兴趣
thinking of how we can instill moral
思考如何灌输道德
values into computers obviously this is
显然这是计算机的价值
not something we'll achieve in the next
不是我们接下来会实现的
five or ten years how can we you know
五年或十年 你怎么知道
there's already work in detecting
还有的 检测 工作已经
emotions for example in images and
例如在图像 和 图像中的情感
sounds and texts and also studying how
声音和文本，还研究如何
different agents interacting in
不同的代理人互动
different ways may correspond to
不同的方式可能对应
patterns of say injustice which could
说不公正的模式可以
trigger anger so these are things we can
引发愤怒，这些都是我们能做到的
do in in the medium term and eventually
在中期和最终做
train computers to model for example how
训练计算机模型， 例如如何
humans react emotionally I would say the
人类情绪反应我会 说
simplest thing is unfair situations
最简单的事情是不公平的情况
which trigger anger this is one of the
这引发了愤怒，这是其中 之一
most basic emotions that we share with
我们分享的最基本的情感
other animals I think it's quite
其他动物 我认为 这是相当的
feasible within the next few years so we
在未来几年内是可行的 ，所以我们
can build systems that can
可以建立系统 ，可以
take these kind of things to the extent
在某种程度上采取这些事情
unfortunately that they understand
不幸的是他们明白了
enough about the world around us which
足够关于 我们 周围的世界
is a long time away but maybe we can
是很长一段时间， 但也许我们可以
initially do this in virtual
最初在虚拟中这样做
environments so you can imagine like a
环境， 所以你可以想像 一个
video game we're agents interact in in
视频游戏我们是代理商互动的
some ways and then some situations
某些方式，然后一些情况
trigger an emotion I think we could
引发一种情绪， 我想我们可以
train machines to detect those
训练机器来检测那些
situations and predict that the
情况和预测，
particular emotion you know will likely
你知道的特殊情绪很可能
be felt if a human was playing one of
如果一个人正在玩其中一个，就会感觉到
the characters you have shown excitement
你 表现出兴奋 的人物
and done a lot of excellent work with
并做了很多 出色的工作与
supervised learning but on a superbug
监督学习， 但在一个 超级细菌
you know there's been a lot of success
你知道有 很多成功
on the supervised learning yes yes and
关于监督学习 是的 和
one of the things I'm really passionate
我 真正热爱 的事情 之一
about is how humans and robots work
关于人类和机器人的工作方式
together and in the context of
在...的背景下
supervised learning that means the
监督学习这意味着
process of annotation do you think about
你想到的注释过程
the problem of annotation of put in a
注入问题的问题
more interesting way is humans teaching
更有趣的方式是人类教学
machines yes is there yes I think it's
机器是的，是的，我认为 是的
an important subject reducing it to
一个重要的主题， 减少它
annotation may be useful for somebody
注释可能对某人有用
building a system tomorrow but
明天 建立一个 系统 但是
longer-term the process of teaching I
长期 的教学过程我
think is something that deserves a lot
认为是值得的
more attention from the machine learning
更多来自机器学习的关注
community so there are people have
社区所以有人有
coined the term machine teaching so what
创造了机器教学这个术语
are good strategies for teaching a
教学 的好策略
learning agent and can we design train a
学习代理人， 我们可以设计培训
system that gonna be is gonna be a good
系统会 是是要去是一个很好的
teacher so so in my group we have a
老师，所以在我的小组中，我们有一个
project called the baby I or baby I game
项目叫宝贝我或宝贝我比赛
where there is a game or scenario where
哪里有游戏或 场景
there's a learning agent and a teaching
有学习代理和教学
agent presumably the teaching agent
代理人大概是教学代理人
would eventually be a human but we're
最终会是一个人， 但我们是
not there yet and the the role of the
现在 还没有和的的作用
teacher is to use its knowledge of the
老师是 用它的知识
environment which it can acquire using
它可以获得的环境
whatever way brute force to help the
任何方式蛮力 帮助
learner learn as quickly as possible so
学习者尽快学到
the learner is going to try to learn by
学习者将尝试 学习
it
它
of maybe be using some exploration and
也许是在使用一些探索和
whatever but the teacher can choose can
除了老师可以选择的 任何东西
can can have an influence on the
可以对...产生影响
interaction with the learner so as to
与学习者的互动以便
guide the learner maybe teach it the
指导学习者可能会 教它
things that the learner has most trouble
学习者最麻烦的事情
with or just at the boundary between
与...或仅在边界 之间
what it knows and doesn't know and so on
它知道什么， 不知道等等
so this is there's a tradition of these
所以这就是这些传统
kind of ideas from other fields and like
来自其他领域和类似的想法
tutorial systems for example and they I
例如教程系统和 他们 我
and and of course people in the
并且，当然人 在
humanities have been thinking about
人文一直在思考
these questions but I think it's time
这些问题，但 我认为 是时候了
that machine learning people look at
机器 学习人们看
this because in the future we'll have
这是因为将来 我们会有
more and more human machine interaction
越来越多的人机交互
with a human in the loop and I think
我认为， 人类 在循环中
understanding how to make this work
了解如何使这项工作
better all the problems around that are
更好的是周围的所有问题
very interesting and not sufficiently
非常有趣而且 不够充分
addressed you've done a lot of work with
解决了你做了很多工作
language to what aspect of the
语言到了什么方面
traditionally formulated Turing test a
传统配方的图灵测试a
test of natural language understanding a
自然语言理解测试a
generation in your eyes is the most
你眼中的一代是最多的
difficult of conversation but in your
谈话很困难， 但在你 的谈话 中
eyes is the hardest part of conversation
眼睛是谈话中最难的部分
to solve for machines so I would say
我会说，解决机器问题
it's everything having to do with the
它与一切有关
non linguistic knowledge which
非语言知识
implicitly you need in order to make
隐含地你需要为了做
sense of sentences things like the
句子之类的感觉就像
Winograd schemas so these sentences that
Winograd架构所以这些句子
are semantically ambiguous in other
在其他方面是语义模糊的
words you need to understand enough
你需要充分理解的话
about the world in order to really
关于世界， 才能 真正
interpret probably those sentences I
可能解释那些句子 我
think these are interesting challenges
认为这些是有趣的挑战
for our machine learning because they
我们的机器 学习因为他们
point in the direction of building
指向建筑的方向
systems that both understand how the
系统都知道如何
world works and it's causal
世界运作 ，这是因果关系
relationships in the world and associate
世界和同事之间的关系
that knowledge with how to express it in
关于如何表达它的知识
language either for reading or writing
用于阅读或写作的语言
you speak French yes it's my mother
你说法语是的，这是我的母亲
tongue it's one of the Romance languages
舌头它是浪漫语言之一
do you think passing the Turing test and
你认为通过图灵测试 和
all the underlying challenges we just
我们所有的潜在挑战
mentioned depend on language do you
提到依靠语言你呢
think it might be easier in front
认为它可能更容易在前面
that is in English now is independent of
现在 用英语 是独立 的
language mmm
语言嗯
I think it's independent of language I I
我认为这是独立的语言， 我的我
would like to build systems that can use
想建立可以使用的系统
the same principles the same learning
同样的原则相同的学习
mechanisms to learn from human agents
从人类代理人那里学习的机制
whatever their language well certainly
无论他们的语言当然如何
us humans can talk more beautifully and
我们人类可以更美妙地说话
smoothly in poetry some Russian
一些俄罗斯诗歌顺利
originally I know poetry and Russian is
最初我知道诗歌 和俄罗斯是
maybe easier to convey complex ideas
也许更容易传达复杂的想法
than it is in English but maybe I'm
比起英文，但也许是我
showing my bias and some people could
显示我的偏见，有些人可以
say that about front half French but of
说一下前半法语但
course the goal ultimately is our human
当然，目标最终是我们的人类
brain is able to utilize any kind of
大脑能够 利用任何种类的
those languages to use them as tools to
那些语言将它们用作 工具
convey meaning you know of course there
传达你当然知道的意思
are differences between languages and
语言和语言之间 的差异
maybe some are slightly better at some
也许有些人在某些方面略胜一筹
things but in the grand scheme of things
事物， 但在 宏伟的 计划中
where we're trying to understand how the
在哪里我们试图 了解如何
brain works and language and so on
大脑工作 和语言等
I think these differences are a minut so
我认为这些差异是微不足道的
you've lived perhaps through an AI
你可能通过AI生活过
winter of sorts yes how did you stay
各种各样的冬天， 你是怎么待的
warm and continue and you're resurfacing
温暖并 继续， 你正在重新铺设
stay warm with friends and with friends
与朋友和朋友保持温暖
okay so it's important to have friends
好的，所以有朋友很重要
and what have you learned from the
你从中学到了 什么 ？
experience listen to your inner voice
经验听你内心的声音
don't you know be trying to just please
难道你不知道要试着取悦
the crowds and the fashion and if you
人群和时尚 ，如果你
have a strong intuition about something
对某事有强烈的直觉
that is not contradicted by actual
这与 实际 并不矛盾
evidence go for it I mean it could be
它的证据去 我的意思是 它可能是
contradicted by people but not your own
与人相矛盾但不是你 自己
instinct of based on everything you know
基于你所知道的一切的本能
of course of course you have to adapt
当然， 你必须适应
your beliefs when your experiments
你的实验时的信念
contradict those beliefs but but you
与那些信仰相矛盾但是你
have to stick to your beliefs otherwise
必须坚持自己的信仰 ，否则
it's it's it's what allowed me to go
就是这就是让我走的路
through those years it's what allowed me
通过这些年来，这是允许我的
to
至
persist in directions that you know took
坚持你所知道的方向
time whatever all the people think took
所有人都认为的时间
time to mature and you bring fruits so
时间成熟，你带来水果
history of AI is marked with these of
人工智能的历史标志着这些
course it's mark with technical
当然，它标志着 技术
breakthroughs but it's also marked with
突破但它也标 有
these seminal events that capture the
这些开创性的事件捕获了
imagination of the community most recent
最近社区的想象力
I would say alphago beating the world
我会说alphago击败世界
champion human go player was one of
冠军人类去球员是其中之一
those moments what do you think the next
那些时刻你认为下一个是什么
such moment might be okay surface first
这样的时刻可能是好的 表面
of all I think that these so-called
所有我认为这些所谓的
seminal events are overrated as I said
正如我所说，开创性事件被高估了
science really moves by small steps now
科学现在真的是小步骤
what happens is you make one more small
会发生什么让你变得更小
step and it's like the the drop that you
一步，这就像 你 的下降
know allows to that fills the bucket and
知道允许填充桶和
and and then you have drastic
然后你就变得激烈了
consequences because now you're able to
后果，因为现在你能够
do something you were not able to do
做一些 你无法做的事
before or now say the cost of building
之前或现在 说建筑的成本
some device or solving a problem becomes
某些设备或解决问题就变成了
cheaper than what existed and you have a
比现有的便宜， 你有一个
new market that opens up right so so
它开创 了权利，使这样的新市场
especially in the world of Commerce and
特别是在 商业 和 世界
applications the impact of a small
应用程序的影响很小
scientific progress could be huge but in
科学进步可能是 巨大的， 但 在
the science itself I think it's very
科学本身我 认为非常
very gradual and where these steps being
非常渐进，这些步骤在哪里
taken now so there's supervised right so
现在采取这样的 监督是 正确的
if I look at one trend that I like in in
如果我看到一个趋势，我喜欢 在
in my community so for example in at me
在我的社区中， 例如在我身边
lie in my Institute what are the two
躺在 我的研究所这两个是什么
hottest topics Gans and rain for
最热门的话题甘和 雨
spurning even though in the montreal in
即使在蒙特利尔，也会嗤之以鼻
particular like reinforcement learning
特别喜欢强化学习
was something pretty much absent just
只是缺少一些东西
two or three years ago so it is really a
两三 年前所以它真的是一个
big interest from students and there's a
学生们非常感兴趣，并且有一个
big interest from people like me
像我这样的人很感兴趣
so I would say this is something where
所以我会说这是什么 地方
are we gonna see more progress even
我们甚至会看到更多的进展吗？
though it hasn't yet provided much in
虽然它 尚未提供太多内容
terms of actual industrial fallout like
实际 工业后果的条款如
even though there's alphago there's no
即使有alphago也没有
like Google is not making money on this
像谷歌这样没有赚钱
right now but I think over the long term
现在，但我认为 从长远来看
this is really really important for many
这对许多人 来说真的很重要
reasons so in other words agent I would
原因所以换句话说代理 我 会
say reinforcement learning baby more
说加强学习宝贝 更多
generally agent learning because it
通常是代理学习，因为它
doesn't have to be with rewards it could
它不一定是奖励
be in all kinds of ways that an agent is
以一种代理人的各种方式
learning about its environment now
现在就了解它的环境
reinforced learning you're excited about
强化 学习你很兴奋
do you think do you think Gans could
你认为 甘斯能 做到吗？
provide something yes some moment in in
在某些时刻提供一些东西
a well Gans or other generative models I
一个井Gans或其他生成模型我
believe will be crucial ingredients in
相信将是至关重要的因素
building agents that can understand the
能够理解的建筑代理商
world a lot of the successes in
世界上很多 成功的
reinforcement learning in the past has
在过去的强化学习 有
been with policy gradient where you
在你所处的政策梯度
you'll just learn a policy you don't
你只需要学习一项你没有的政策
actually learn a model of the world but
实际上是学习世界的模型而已
there are lots of issues with that and
有很多的问题， 与 和
we don't know how to do model-based our
我们不知道如何做 基于模型的我们
rel right now but I think this is where
现在版本 ，但我认为这是哪里
we have to go in order to build models
我们必须去建立模型
that can generalize faster and better
这可以 更快 更好地 推广
like to new distributions that capture
喜欢捕捉的新发行版
to some extent at least the underlying
在某种程度上至少是潜在的
causal mechanisms in in the world last
最后的世界因果机制
question what made you fall in love with
是什么让你 爱上了
artificial intelligence if you look back
人工智能 ，如果你回头看
what was the first moment in your life
你生命中的第一刻是什么时候
when he's when you were fascinated by
当他被你迷住的时候
either the human mind or the artificial
无论是人类的头脑还是人造的
mind you know when I wasn't at the
记住，当我不在时 ， 你知道
lesson I was reading a lot and then I I
我读了很多课， 然后是II
started reading science fiction there
开始在那里 阅读科幻小说
you go but I got that's that's it that
你去了，但我得到的就是这样
that's that's where I got hooked and
这就是我迷上了的地方
then and then you know I had one of the
再 然后，你知道我 的 一个
first personal computers and I got
第一台 个人电脑和我
hooked in programming and so it just you
迷上了编程，所以它 就是你
know start with fiction and then make it
知道从小说开始然后成功
a reality that's right
一个 正确 的现实
Yoshio thank you so much for talking to
Yoshio非常感谢你的谈话
my pleasure
我的荣幸
you
您